<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>sketches</title>
    <atom:link href="sketches.kevinsalter.me/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
    <link>sketches.kevinsalter.me</link>
    <description>✍</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 06  Aug 2015 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <generator>Wintersmith - https://github.com/jnordberg/wintersmith</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>starting to imagine mobile recognition</title>
      <link>sketches.kevinsalter.me/articles/4-mobile-recognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06  Aug 2015 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">sketches.kevinsalter.me/articles/4-mobile-recognition/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While there are debates around how a modern employee recognition program might operate, it’s clear that there is tremendous value in being able to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.officevibe.com/facegame&quot;&gt;recognize your colleagues&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
…
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Seriously though, it’s obvious that showing appreciation and receiving kudos from teammates builds morale and makes people feel more connected to each other.  But should it be a core focus of a company, or is it just an annoying thing aimed at ‘millennials’?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-7geese-flavour-of-love-recognition&quot;&gt;The 7Geese flavour of &lt;del&gt;love&lt;/del&gt; recognition&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At 7Geese, recognition badges represent a company’s core values; awarding badges to colleagues then helps strengthen each person’s alignment to those values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love that simplicity.  It’s also a really nice parallel to the way OKRs strengthen the alignment of everyone’s goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-is-recognition-good-for-&quot;&gt;What is recognition good for?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For many 7Geese users, being recognized by a co-worker is a &lt;a href=&quot;http://genius.com/Alex-schultz-lecture-6-growth-annotated&quot;&gt;“magic moment”&lt;/a&gt;– an instant where a user feels the platform delivering its core value and building its stickiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since recognition can come from anyone (peers, managers, reports) it can help to unify teams, proactively reinforce good performance, and foster a sense of appreciation and belonging across the entire team.  New employees being on-boarded can quickly get a direct sense of what that company is about.  And the public nature of recognition means people are noticing that your work is getting noticed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zooming out a bit, the trend of recognition given over a period of time could be an interesting data point for company leaders to help gauge employees’ alignment to the company’s core values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;arguments-against-recognition-and-way-better-counterarguments-&quot;&gt;Arguments against recognition (…and way better counterarguments)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s also important to define what recognition is &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt;– &lt;em&gt;i.e.&lt;/em&gt; it doesn’t acknowledge any employee’s tenure, metrics or stats related to their job (there are no leaderboards!), and it’s not meant to gamify an employee’s training experience (meaning, you don’t get a ‘prize’ after each level), for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That being said, there are still a few arguments we’ve received against recognition’s effectiveness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most reasonable one I’ve heard so far is that it can be annoying at larger companies to see a feed full of recognitions, some of which you may not care about.  There’s likely a case to be made for allowing users to opt in/out of which recognitions hit their feed and, conversely, if employees wanted to be more private, and limit the publicity of recognitions they have received (even though that kind of defeats the purpose…).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another complaint is that people are being recognized too frequently, and that it can feel like a bit of a popularity contest.  The answer to this could be as simple as teaching people to ask &lt;em&gt;“Is this something that could happen everyday?”&lt;/em&gt;, and if the answer is &lt;em&gt;yes&lt;/em&gt;, it’s not recognition.  Recognition must me authentic and genuine, or else it’s not worth the pixels on the screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also think it’d be an interesting experiment to limit the frequency of recognitions– &lt;code&gt;more scarcity == more valuable&lt;/code&gt;.  For example, maybe you can only give out 1 recognition per week, or only recognize one person per month.  The purpose wouldn’t be to limit users, but just ensure some common sense guidelines were being followed.  The details would have to be worked out, but it might help people to give proper consideration before recognizing someone, and make recognitions harder to ‘abuse’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, there’s the argument that “I’m not a millennial, I don’t need to be recognized for doing my job.”  In my opinion, that’s straight bull$h!t.  But don’t take my word for it!  Harvard Medical School published an article a few years ago explaining how &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.health.harvard.edu/newsletter_article/in-praise-of-gratitude&quot;&gt;gratitude helps people feel more positive emotions, relish good experiences, improve their health, deal with adversity, and build strong relationships&lt;/a&gt;.  And Harvard is never wrong, so…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;is-mobile-the-right-format-&quot;&gt;Is mobile the right format?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since our Q3 meeting, I’ve been interested in the idea of each module of 7Geese being its own mobile app.  It makes sense, since we have some customers who only use (or only &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; to use) 7Geese for recognition, or only for 1-on-1s.  So it makes sense to think for a minute about why mobile would be a good format for an individual module like recognition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the simplest terms, the act of giving recognition is quick and easy to do.  It’s an impulsive action that doesn’t require any preparation.  I could be on the SkyTrain on my way home from the office and remember that I wanted to recognize a colleague.  I whip out my phone, and 💥.  That kind of ease would also facilitate timely recognition which, as we know, &lt;a href=&quot;http://support.7geese.com/hc/en-us/articles/204411167-Tips-On-Recognizing-a-Teammate&quot;&gt;(is more effective)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;some-mobile-best-practices&quot;&gt;Some mobile best practices&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are a few considerations when designing a mobile experience:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;elements should be sized appropriately&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;design for fat fingers, pictorial icons&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://tympanus.net/Development/CardExpansion/&quot;&gt;use animations&lt;/a&gt;, maybe &lt;a href=&quot;http://tympanus.net/Development/AnimatedSVGIcons/&quot;&gt;SVG morphing icons&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;this is supposed to be fun!!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there might be better &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lukew.com/ff/entry.asp?1950&quot;&gt;alternatives to dropdowns&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how does the navigation work?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how many clicks/swipes are required to accomplish a certain task?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://uxmyths.com/post/654026581/myth-all-pages-should-be-accessible-in-3-clicks&quot;&gt;not that that matters?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mobile internet is slow&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;is the app simple, and the payload to the browser as small as it can be?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;design patterns: &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.intercom.io/why-cards-are-the-future-of-the-web/&quot;&gt;cards&lt;/a&gt; vs &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.uxpin.com/6774/5-creative-mobile-ui-patterns-navigation/&quot;&gt;grids&lt;/a&gt; vs &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nngroup.com/articles/image-vs-list-mobile-navigation/&quot;&gt;lists&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how much of the app can i navigate using only one hand?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-are-some-of-the-screens-we-ll-need-&quot;&gt;What are some of the screens we’ll need?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;login&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;navigation&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I’m leaning towards a fullscreen nav motif throughout the app (i.e. popovers, dialogs, and navigation would all take up the full screen while they’re being used)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;browse colleagues&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;also browse departments or teams?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;choosing a colleague then opens recognition form with the person pre-selected&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;recognition form (for giving recognition)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;recognize individuals, groups, and departments?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;choose user(s)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;write description&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;choose badge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;checkbox: notify recipient’s manager? department(s)?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;list (feed) of recognition given out&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;ability to filter by person / team / badge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;each list item links to individual recognition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ability to “like” or share without having to go to individual recognition (swipe left on iOS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;individual recognition pages&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;with comments&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;ability to “like”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;social sharing&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;social sharing button’s overlay/dialog (full screen)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;list of available badges with descriptions&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;choosing a badge shows the description of that badge (full screen)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;when in full screen, there’s an ‘x’ to close the overlay, and a CTA button to give that badge to someone, which then opens the recognition form with that badge pre-selected&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Admins:&lt;/em&gt; create and edit badges&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;badge name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;description of badge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;which departments can use it?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;upload an image&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;by the way, Digital Ocean has &lt;a href=&quot;http://drbl.in/mZXI&quot;&gt;some really nicely designed core values badges&lt;/a&gt;, worth checking out&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article-end&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;annotation&quot;&gt;
    each rectangle is the size of an iPhone 6 screen
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://placeholdit.imgix.net/~text?txtsize=33&amp;amp;txt=wait%20for%20it...&amp;amp;w=800&amp;amp;h=500&quot; alt=&quot;Pic 1&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OKR builder concept</title>
      <link>sketches.kevinsalter.me/articles/3-okr-builder-concept/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">sketches.kevinsalter.me/articles/3-okr-builder-concept/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week’s sketch and concept started out as something I just thought would be funny– the idea that as you enter your objectives and key results into fields in the UI, the software “lints” your input and gives you feedback akin to a spell-checker.  But in the end, I realized that it actually has a couple of interesting connections to how a tech product delivers core value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More on that in a minute, but first:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;okr-builder-and-linter-concept&quot;&gt;OKR Builder (and linter) Concept&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is really conceptual, since a good OKR has so many subjective qualities (i.e. it’s difficult to algorithmically determine if an objective is “attainable, but still ambitious like a stretch goal” or if it aligns with a company’s “organizational culture”).  Then again, if I’m using the spell-checker analogy, a spell-checker can’t ensure your writing is grammatically correct and elegant, so it kind of works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the sketches below, the interface is essentially a blank screen (à la Medium) with a field for the user to enter their first objective.  The user would press &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;tab&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; to jump from the objective to each key result, with new fields appearing as the user progresses (so, ideally no clicking would be required to create 3 objectives with 3 key results).  As the user types, the words are scanned on every keystroke, and feedback is given to the user based on what they’ve entered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, I’ve noticed that 99% of objectives that I’ve seen defined in the OKR pattern begin with a verb (i.e. Increase, Reduce, Improve, Implement, etc.), so that would be helpful feedback to show the user.  For key results, the possibilities might be even more numerous considering they’re more quantitative in nature.  In fact, most key results contain numbers, which is another data-point that an OKR builder could look for in the user’s input.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; the example OKR in the sketches below is completely contrived (obvs), and only intended for demonstration purposes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, if I were to imagine a set of OKR linting rules as a config file similar to those we use in code linters, it might look something like this, &lt;code&gt;okr-linter.json&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
    &amp;quot;no_leading_verb_in_objectives&amp;quot;: {
        &amp;quot;level&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;error&amp;quot;
    },
    &amp;quot;numbers_in_objectives&amp;quot;: {
        &amp;quot;level&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;warn&amp;quot;
    },
    &amp;quot;too_many_ands_in_objective&amp;quot;: {
        &amp;quot;level&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;warn&amp;quot;
    },
    &amp;quot;no_numbers_in_keyresults&amp;quot;: {
        &amp;quot;level&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;error&amp;quot;
    }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h4 id=&quot;connecting-some-dots&quot;&gt;Connecting Some Dots&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the largest challenges at any tech company is onboarding.  And, when it comes to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.preact.com/saas-churn-causes-and-prevention&quot;&gt;leading causes of churn in SaaS products&lt;/a&gt;, it’s often a huge factor.  At 7Geese it’s especially interesting since we’re also selling our customers on the adoption and implementation of the OKR methodology, as well as the software platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another challenge that any tech company faces is forming some kind of “growth hacking” strategy.  For example, Facebook used the metric of getting users to “10 friends in 14 days” as a benchmark for deciding if users were adequately engaged with the product and would receive enough of the core value of the product to a level where they would be retained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, to combine those ideas, imagine this OKR builder tool were set up in such a way that it required the user to create “3 objectives with 3 key results every 3 months”, and then guided the user through the process with automatic, instant feedback. 💥&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s obviously an over-simplification, but it’s food for thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article-end&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;annotation&quot;&gt;
    okr builder concept
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/3-okr-builder-concept/1-okr-builder-overview.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;OKR Builder Concept Sketch&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;annotation&quot;&gt;
    ‘objective starts with a verb’ error tooltip
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/3-okr-builder-concept/2-objective-verb-error-tooltip.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Objective Starts with Verb Error Tooltip&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;annotation&quot;&gt;
    ‘objective contains a number’ warning tooltip
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/3-okr-builder-concept/3-objective-warning-tooltip.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Objective Number Warning Tooltip&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;annotation&quot;&gt;
    ‘objective’s scope is possibly too broad’ warning tooltip
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/3-okr-builder-concept/4-objective-and-warning-tooltip.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Objective Uses And Warning Tooltip&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;annotation&quot;&gt;
    ‘key result doesn’t contain a number’ error tooltip
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/3-okr-builder-concept/5-kr-error-tooltip.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Key Result Number Error Tooltip&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1-on-1 scheduling alerts</title>
      <link>sketches.kevinsalter.me/articles/2-1-on-1-alert/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">sketches.kevinsalter.me/articles/2-1-on-1-alert/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This quick sketch was inspired by the upcoming 1-on-1 scheduling project for 7Geese, and also the proposed “Explore new Information Architecture (IA) approaches for 7Geese” project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea of the platform shifting from being objective oriented (lol… no? …) to being focused on talent management and employees (as proposed in the IA project definition) is actually quite profound.  To me, at the highest level, it’s the difference between whether I keep the 7Geese application open in a browser tab all day, every day, or only open it once a week to check into my objectives.  Huge difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To expand on that, if the application is going to be open all the time, it will be because it’s giving me new and direct feedback.  As a user, I’ll then want to treat the app as a dashboard for project related progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How is my team doing, especially on the projects I’m directly involved in?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where am I needed?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What should I do next?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Answering these questions for users could improve a couple of the answers that Dave recently received from users to the question &lt;a href=&quot;https://7geese.atlassian.net/wiki/pages/viewpage.action?pageId=12714000&quot;&gt;Can you tell us why you checked-in today?&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;1-on-1-alert&quot;&gt;1-on-1 Alert&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a culture of Continuous Performance Management, the habit of regular 1-on-1s is vital.  Furthermore, if you have a management role, this can involve participating in different 1-on-1s as both a facilitator and subject.  The case can then be made for the value of having a prominent alert that keeps the user engaged in the 1-on-1 workflows within 7Geese.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The top-right area of the navigation seems like a logical place for an alert like this to live since it would be close to other in-app notifications.  Inside the popover the user is presented with a concise, plain English representation of their pending 1-on-1 commitments (basically, any 1-on-1s that are in Draft Mode for that user).  There are two possible actions that can be performed on each list item:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;click the calendar icon to go directly to Google calendar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;clicking the body of the message would redirect the user to the individual page for that particular 1-on-1.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article-end&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;annotation&quot;&gt;
    scheduled 1-on-1 alert concept
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/2-1-on-1-alert/1-on-1-alert.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;1-on-1 Alert Concept Sketch&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>the gameplan</title>
      <link>sketches.kevinsalter.me/articles/1-gameplan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2015 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">sketches.kevinsalter.me/articles/1-gameplan/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, I’ve created an &lt;a href=&quot;https://7geese.com/okrs/&quot;&gt;OKR&lt;/a&gt; for my Q3 at &lt;a href=&quot;http://7geese.com&quot;&gt;7Geese&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;“Improve my ability to think critically about feature design/implementation and strengthen user empathy through sketching” &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-1&quot; style=&quot;text-decoration:none;&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, and tagged it with the &lt;code class=&quot;learn-and-grow&quot;&gt;Learning and Growth&lt;/code&gt; label.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I’ve been meaning to get back to sketching UI and UX workflow ideas for a while now.  It’s a great way to brainstorm and explore ideas &lt;em&gt;away from the computer&lt;/em&gt; for several reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it’s the fastest/cheapest way to ideate and explore a few trains of thought quickly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;thinking with your hands and physical tools like pencil and paper provide a nice change in pace from digital tools&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sketching is low fidelity, which tends to invite commentary and foster better conversations around the ideas being presented&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, with so many interesting things on the 7Geese feature roadmap, this will be a useful way jot down some ideas before we form teams and start building things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;footnote-1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;
    &lt;strong class=&quot;pull-left&quot; style=&quot;margin-right:10px;&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;div&gt;My objective was previously called “12 sketches in 12 weeks”, but I improved it after watching &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/133095368&quot;&gt;Creating a GREAT OKR and Quarterly Planning Process&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;article-end&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;annotation&quot;&gt;
    sketches from past projects
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/1-gameplan/dashboard-sketch.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dashboard Sketch&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/1-gameplan/phone-sketch.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Phone Sketch&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>