<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>sketches</title>
    <atom:link href="sketches.kevinsalter.me/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
    <link>sketches.kevinsalter.me</link>
    <description>✍</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <generator>Wintersmith - https://github.com/jnordberg/wintersmith</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>1-on-1 scheduling alerts</title>
      <link>sketches.kevinsalter.me/articles/2-1-on-1-alert/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">sketches.kevinsalter.me/articles/2-1-on-1-alert/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This quick sketch was inspired by the upcoming 1-on-1 scheduling project for 7Geese, and also the proposed “Explore new Information Architecture (IA) approaches for 7Geese” project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, the idea of the platform shifting from being objective oriented (lol… no? …) to being focused on talent management and employees is actually quite profound.  To me, at the highest level, it’s the difference between whether I keep the 7Geese application open in a browser tab all day, every day, or only open it once a week to check into my objectives.  Huge difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To expand on that, if the application is going to be open all the time, it will be because it’s giving me direct feedback.  As a user, I’ll want to treat the app as a dashboard for project related progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How is my team doing, especially on the projects I’m directly involved in?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where am I needed?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What should I do next?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Answering these questions for users could improve a couple of the answers that Dave recently received from users to the question &lt;a href=&quot;https://7geese.atlassian.net/wiki/pages/viewpage.action?pageId=12714000&quot;&gt;Can you tell us why you checked-in today?&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;1-on-1-alert&quot;&gt;1-on-1 Alert&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a culture of Continuous Performance Management, the habit of regular 1-on-1s is vital.  Furthermore, if you have a management role, this can involve participating in different 1-on-1s as both a facilitator and subject.  The case can then be made for the value of having a prominent alert that keeps the user engaged in the 1-on-1 workflows within 7Geese.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The top-right of the navigation seems like a logical place for an alert like this to live since it would be close to other in-app notifications.  Inside the popover the user is presented with a concise, plain English representation of their pending 1-on-1 commitments.  There a two possible actions that can be performed on each list item: &lt;em&gt;1.&lt;/em&gt; click the calendar icon to go directly to Google calendar; and &lt;em&gt;2.&lt;/em&gt; clicking the body of the message would redirect the user to the individual page for that particular 1-on-1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article-end&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;annotation&quot;&gt;
    scheduled 1-on-1 alert concept
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/2-1-on-1-alert/1-on-1-alert.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;1-on-1 Alert&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>the gameplan</title>
      <link>sketches.kevinsalter.me/articles/1-gameplan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2015 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">sketches.kevinsalter.me/articles/1-gameplan/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, I’ve created an &lt;a href=&quot;https://7geese.com/okrs/&quot;&gt;OKR&lt;/a&gt; for my Q3 at &lt;a href=&quot;http://7geese.com&quot;&gt;7Geese&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;“Improve my ability to think critically about feature design/implementation and strengthen user empathy through sketching” &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-1&quot; style=&quot;text-decoration:none;&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, and tagged it with the &lt;code class=&quot;learn-and-grow&quot;&gt;Learning and Growth&lt;/code&gt; label.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I’ve been meaning to get back to sketching UI and UX workflow ideas for a while now.  It’s a great way to brainstorm and explore ideas &lt;em&gt;away from the computer&lt;/em&gt; for several reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it’s the fastest/cheapest way to ideate and explore a few trains of thought quickly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;thinking with your hands and physical tools like pencil and paper provide a nice change in pace from digital tools&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sketching is low fidelity, which tends to invite commentary and foster better conversations around the ideas being presented&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, with so many interesting things on the 7Geese feature roadmap, this will be a useful way jot down some ideas before we form teams and start building things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;footnote-1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;
    &lt;strong class=&quot;pull-left&quot; style=&quot;margin-right:10px;&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;div&gt;My objective was previously called “12 sketches in 12 weeks”, but I improved it after watching &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/133095368&quot;&gt;Creating a GREAT OKR and Quarterly Planning Process&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;article-end&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;annotation&quot;&gt;
    sketches from past projects
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/1-gameplan/dashboard-sketch.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dashboard Sketch&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/1-gameplan/phone-sketch.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Phone Sketch&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>