<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>sketches</title>
    <atom:link href="sketches.kevinsalter.me/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
    <link>sketches.kevinsalter.me</link>
    <description>✍</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <generator>Wintersmith - https://github.com/jnordberg/wintersmith</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>ia sketches</title>
      <link>sketches.kevinsalter.me/articles/10-ia-sketches/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">sketches.kevinsalter.me/articles/10-ia-sketches/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Information Architecture (IA)&lt;/strong&gt; is… um, a lot of things.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
    &lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;– me, paraphrasing &lt;em&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the purposes of this exercise, I think it’s fair to classify “information architecture” as &lt;span style=&quot;background: lavender;&quot;&gt;the organization, labeling, navigation system, and layout of a web application to better support its usability and key workflows&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;design-constraints&quot;&gt;Design Constraints&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to tame the infinite possibilities of this design, we came up with some constraints to better frame the problem we’re trying to solve.  This will also help to measure if new designs have been successful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;border-bottom: 1px solid #555;padding-bottom: 2px;&quot;&gt;Target Roles:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; Team Member, Manager (2 of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://7geese.atlassian.net/wiki/display/PD/Compiled+Workflows&quot;&gt;4 roles&lt;/a&gt; we’ve defined)&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;border-bottom: 1px solid #555;padding-bottom: 2px;&quot;&gt;Typical Example Network:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; We’re imagining that this design is targeted at a company with 50+ employees that has departments set and runs performance management processes (which were set up at least 6 months ago) using 1 or more of 7Geese’s core features &lt;em&gt;(OKRs, Cycles, Recognition, Feedback, 1-on-1s)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;border-bottom: 1px solid #555;padding-bottom: 2px;&quot;&gt;Ultimate Goal:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; Better enable users to succeed with their company’s performance management process.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;border-bottom: 1px solid #555;padding-bottom: 2px;&quot;&gt;Execution Time:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; The new design should be able to be implemented by the dev team within a 3-month timespan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;-my-daily-routine-with-7geese-&quot;&gt;“My Daily Routine with 7Geese”&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was the title of a blog post I was working on before the IA project came to be.  The idea emerged during a chat with Max at one of our front-end meetings where we asked: “Why doesn’t 7Geese just tell me what to do, or at least where to start?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, it’s the same question we’re asking in this project: “How can we help users be successful with their company’s PM process?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s a great start, but what could that look like?  Could 7Geese generate relevant, actionable TODO lists based on a user’s activity and position in the org chart?  Maybe we could set up scheduled &lt;a href=&quot;http://sketches.kevinsalter.me/articles/2-1-on-1-alert/&quot;&gt;alerts&lt;/a&gt; that remind users at certain times to give certain tasks attention?  Would a “follow model”, à la Twitter, help users focus on messages and notifications they care about, and ignore information that is irrelevant?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favourite idea that’s been suggested so far is that the homepage could function more as a customized user dashboard.  A lot of information is duplicated between the Cycles page, Profile page, and the current Homepage.  That information could be more relevantly arranged in a way that’s not only informational, but actionable as well.  Personally, this will by the root of my first concepts presented here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;job-stories&quot;&gt;Job Stories&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used the &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.intercom.io/using-job-stories-design-features-ui-ux/&quot;&gt;job stories&lt;/a&gt; paradigm as one technique to channel my thinking throughout this process of exploring the &lt;span style=&quot;background: lavender;&quot;&gt;context, causality, anxieties, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/the-job-to-be-done/5-tips-for-writing-a-job-story-7c9092911fc9#21ab&quot;&gt;motivations and forces&lt;/a&gt; of what 7Geese users do now&lt;/span&gt;.  This paradigm is equally important in helping to avoid focusing on useless items such as assumptions, subjectiveness, personas, and implementations before putting pen to paper.  Finally, I thought that if some of these designs were successful, this pattern might make them &lt;a href=&quot;https://robots.thoughtbot.com/test-driven-product-design&quot;&gt;easier to test&lt;/a&gt; later on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;annotation&quot;&gt;
    As a quick reminder, this is the anatomy of a typical Job Story.
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;sketches.kevinsalter.me/articles/10-ia-sketches/JobStoryAnatomy.png&quot; alt=&quot;job story anatomy&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;-span-style-display-inline-block-border-bottom-1px-solid-555-padding-bottom-2px-margin-bottom-10px-role-team-member-span-&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;display: inline-block;border-bottom: 1px solid #555;padding-bottom: 2px;margin-bottom: 10px;&quot;&gt;Role: Team Member&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I log in to 7Geese…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;…I want to know which objectives haven’t been assessed within the last 2 weeks so I can take action by checking in and updating their assessment status.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;…I want to know if I have a scheduled 1-on-1 coming up that I haven’t prepared for so I can set aside time to prepare for it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;…I want to clearly see my progress on cycle requirements because I’m concerned that I won’t meet my quarterly quotas and I’m concerned that my manager and teammates will see that my objectives are Off Track.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;…I want to see how the progress I have made so far this quarter has contributed to Department and Organizational level OKRs because I want to myself and my colleagues to recognize how I’m contributing to the bigger picture.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;When viewing a list of my teammates…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;…I want to see how their progress is trending because I want to see if I can supprt them in their tasks and/or I want to reconigize them if they’ve done something exceptional.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;-span-style-display-inline-block-border-bottom-1px-solid-555-padding-bottom-2px-margin-bottom-10px-role-manager-span-&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;display: inline-block;border-bottom: 1px solid #555;padding-bottom: 2px;margin-bottom: 10px;&quot;&gt;Role: Manager&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When I log in to 7Geese…&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;…I want to know how my reports are progressing with their OKRs in case I should reach out and ask if they need help becauase I want them to be engaged and On Track.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When viewing a list of my reports…&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;…I want to know who has scheduled and/or prepared their next 1-on-1 and if not, send them a reminder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
As always, &lt;a href=&quot;sketches.kevinsalter.me/articles/10-ia-sketches/#disqus_thread&quot;&gt;leave a comment below if something comes to mind!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;appendix-a-_the-cutting-room-floor_&quot;&gt;Appendix A: &lt;em&gt;the cutting room floor&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s another idea that is a bit too abstract to pursue, but I think is interesting to mention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea is that a user would have an interactive, customizable sub-set of the org chart that they would visually arrange in a way that’s relevant to them. It would actually be like a combination of Google+ circles and a follow model, essentially adding the ability to group people like others in your department, your reports, who you report to, who you’re collaborating with on specific OKRs, etc.  Finally, the visual arrangement of these groups would serve as a kind of custom org chart, and could also possibly affect the types of notifications a user receives regarding things like feedback requests, 1-on-1 reminders, department level OKR updates, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, this is likely more on the impractical side, but cool to imagine.  It’s also harder for me to relate to this concept because it doesn’t apply to companies as small as 7Geese, so it’s harder to reason about pragmatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article-end&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;annotation&quot;&gt;
    user dashboard concept
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://placeholdit.imgix.net/~text?txtsize=33&amp;amp;txt=wait%20for%20it...&amp;amp;w=800&amp;amp;h=500&quot; alt=&quot;dashboard ia sketches&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>motion design (part 2 of 2)</title>
      <link>sketches.kevinsalter.me/articles/9-motion-design-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">sketches.kevinsalter.me/articles/9-motion-design-part-2/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;link href='https://fonts.googleapis.com/css?family=Open+Sans:400,300' rel='stylesheet' type='text/css'&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot; href=&quot;./libs/sweetalert.css&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot; href=&quot;./main.css&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week I’ll be picking up where I left off in &lt;a href=&quot;sketches.kevinsalter.me/articles/9-motion-design-part-2/sketches.kevinsalter.me/articles/8-motion-design-part-1/&quot;&gt;Part 1&lt;/a&gt; and make some animation happen.  At best, the hope is that some of this experimentation yields something useful, or at least some interesting thoughts and dicussion.  At worst, I learned a ton of cool stuff about SVG animation, and did some math.  😄
&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;3-ways-to-animate-svgs-on-the-web&quot;&gt;3 Ways to Animate SVGs on the Web&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turns out there are 3 different ways to animate SVGs, but there is definitely one clear winner.  Sara Soueidan wrote &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.adobe.com/dreamweaver/2015/06/the-state-of-svg-animation.html&quot;&gt;a great post on the Adobe blog&lt;/a&gt; a couple months ago about the details of all 3 methods, but here’s an overall summary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SMIL&lt;/strong&gt; (pronounced “Smile”) is an XML-based language that was created to enable people to write declarative animations.  Essentionally, you just add a tag to the raw SVG data, as seen below in the &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;animate&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tag in this example from &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/SVG/SVG_animation_with_SMIL&quot;&gt;MDN&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;lang-html&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;span class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;svg&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;attribute&quot;&gt;width&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;value&quot;&gt;&quot;300px&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;attribute&quot;&gt;height&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;value&quot;&gt;&quot;100px&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;span class=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;span class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;rect&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;attribute&quot;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;value&quot;&gt;&quot;0&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;attribute&quot;&gt;y&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;value&quot;&gt;&quot;0&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;attribute&quot;&gt;width&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;value&quot;&gt;&quot;300&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;attribute&quot;&gt;height&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;value&quot;&gt;&quot;100&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;attribute&quot;&gt;stroke&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;value&quot;&gt;&quot;black&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;attribute&quot;&gt;stroke-width&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;value&quot;&gt;&quot;1&quot;&lt;/span&gt; /&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
     &lt;span class=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;span class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;circle&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;attribute&quot;&gt;cx&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;value&quot;&gt;&quot;0&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;attribute&quot;&gt;cy&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;value&quot;&gt;&quot;50&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;attribute&quot;&gt;r&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;value&quot;&gt;&quot;15&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;attribute&quot;&gt;fill&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;value&quot;&gt;&quot;blue&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;attribute&quot;&gt;stroke&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;value&quot;&gt;&quot;black&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;attribute&quot;&gt;stroke-width&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;value&quot;&gt;&quot;1&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
     &lt;span class=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;span class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;animate&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;attribute&quot;&gt;attributeName&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;value&quot;&gt;&quot;cx&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;attribute&quot;&gt;from&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;value&quot;&gt;&quot;0&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;attribute&quot;&gt;to&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;value&quot;&gt;&quot;100&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;attribute&quot;&gt;dur&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;value&quot;&gt;&quot;5s&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;attribute&quot;&gt;repeatCount&lt;/span&gt;=&lt;span class=&quot;value&quot;&gt;&quot;indefinite&quot;&lt;/span&gt; /&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
     &lt;span class=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;span class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;circle&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;span class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;svg&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there are a lot more interesting details about this spec, broswer support has always been spotty and Internet Explorer has never supported it.  Finally, SMIL is set to be completely deprecated in Blink (the rendering engine used in Chrome) in favour of CSS and Web Animations, so…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CSS Animations&lt;/strong&gt; are super powerful, and have established themselves as a best practice technique for animatiing DOM elements in a smooth, powerful way that keeps animations within their 60 frames-per-second budget and helps keep the web &lt;a href=&quot;http://jankfree.org/&quot;&gt;jank free&lt;/a&gt;.  However, for animating SVGs there are a couple of areas where CSS trips up.  When it comes to &lt;em&gt;transforms&lt;/em&gt; (i.e. translate, rotate, scale, skew), which are often key elements to full fledged animations, Firefox has some weird quirks and Opera and Internet Explorer don’t recognize CSS transformations on SVG elements at all.  Speaking of which, another downside to using CSS is that IE9 doesn’t support CSS &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/CSS/@keyframes&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;@keyframes&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; animations, so…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;…the winner is, &lt;strong&gt;JavaScript&lt;/strong&gt;!  It kind of makes sense, though– you get all the capabilities of SMIL and CSS, plus you have access to the whole DOM API, the Web Animations API, and all the power of the scripting language itself (variables, loops, functions, etc.).  Add with the fact that it’s possible to make the resulting animations compatible with all browsers, even old versions of IE, this animation method is the clear winner. 🎉&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;which-js-library-to-use-for-svg-animation-&quot;&gt;Which JS library to use for SVG animation?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Managing the boilerplate of animating SVGs, especially timing issues among a group of animations, can get difficult really quickly, so it can help to leverage a JavaScript library.  There were a few great libraries I found and quickly trialed before choosing on for this demo.  Here’s a short list:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://julian.com/research/velocity/&quot;&gt;Velocity.js&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is really cool.  It’s a super-optimized, API compatible, drop-in replacement for jQuery’s &lt;code&gt;$.animate()&lt;/code&gt; method without the performance issues and with broswer compatability going across the the board and all the way back to IE8.  The project was also backed by Stripe, who are known for their cool UI animations.  It’s under the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MIT_License&quot;&gt;MIT License&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://greensock.com/docs/#/HTML5/GSAP/&quot;&gt;GreenSock Animation Platform&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (GSAP) seems to be the best choice for gaining full control over large, complex animations. Their concepts of attaching things to timelines, and grouping animations by labels to be triggered in different orders is some powerful stuff.  It’s under the &lt;a href=&quot;http://greensock.com/standard-license&quot;&gt;Standard “No Charge” GreenSock License&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://snapsvg.io/&quot;&gt;Snap SVG&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is a library that flies under the Adobe flag, but was written by and based on the work of the guy who created &lt;a href=&quot;http://raphaeljs.com/&quot;&gt;Raphaël&lt;/a&gt;.  It claims to make “working with your SVG assets as easy as jQuery makes working with the DOM”, and is compatible across broswers including IE9+.  I found it equally as simple to use the library to draw shapes on the page, or manipulate existing SVGs.  It also has some AJAX capabilities baked in for dynamically grabbing SVGs from whereever and injecting them into the document.  It’s under the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/adobe-webplatform/Snap.svg/blob/master/LICENSE&quot;&gt;Apache 2 License&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this demo I decided to use Snap SVG because I’m just really digging that library right now.  You can geek out on the commented code for this in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kevinsalter/sketches/blob/gh-pages/contents/articles/9-motion-design-part-2/main.js&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;main.js&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.  It took some surprisingly non-trivial &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kevinsalter/sketches/blob/gh-pages/contents/articles/9-motion-design-part-2/main.js#L13-L15&quot;&gt;math&lt;/a&gt; to make the mouth animation appear simple and natural.  You wouldn’t believe how messed up it looked until I finally wrangled it into something passable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, it’s probably also important to frame this demo as a conceptual prototype.  It’s a functional proof of concept, not something that’s designed, polished, and bug free.  The real question being posed here is:  Is an idea like this useful, or totally not?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article-end&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;annotation&quot;&gt;
    SVG animation demo - OKR Grading
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;container&quot;&gt;
&lt;svg version=&quot;1.1&quot; id=&quot;svg&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot; xmlns:xlink=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink&quot; x=&quot;0px&quot; y=&quot;0px&quot;
     width=&quot;500px&quot; height=&quot;500px&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 500 500&quot; enable-background=&quot;new 0 0 500 500&quot; xml:space=&quot;preserve&quot;&gt;

&lt;path id=&quot;mouth&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; stroke=&quot;#E5D0AE&quot; stroke-width=&quot;5&quot; stroke-linecap=&quot;round&quot; stroke-linejoin=&quot;round&quot; stroke-miterlimit=&quot;10&quot; d=&quot;
        M 127.771,351.329 c 0,0 40.860771,0 120.770151,0 c 70.909379,0 120.770152,0 120.770152,0&quot;/&gt;

&lt;g id=&quot;eyes&quot;&gt;
    &lt;circle fill=&quot;#E5D0AE&quot; stroke=&quot;#E5D0AE&quot; stroke-width=&quot;5&quot; stroke-linecap=&quot;round&quot; stroke-linejoin=&quot;round&quot; stroke-miterlimit=&quot;10&quot; cx=&quot;155&quot; cy=&quot;170&quot; r=&quot;7.5&quot;/&gt;

    &lt;circle fill=&quot;#E5D0AE&quot; stroke=&quot;#E5D0AE&quot; stroke-width=&quot;5&quot; stroke-linecap=&quot;round&quot; stroke-linejoin=&quot;round&quot; stroke-miterlimit=&quot;10&quot; cx=&quot;345&quot; cy=&quot;170&quot; r=&quot;7.5&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/g&gt;

&lt;circle id=&quot;face-outline&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; stroke=&quot;#E5D0AE&quot; stroke-width=&quot;5&quot; stroke-linecap=&quot;round&quot; stroke-linejoin=&quot;round&quot; stroke-miterlimit=&quot;10&quot; cx=&quot;250&quot; cy=&quot;250&quot; r=&quot;244.275&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/svg&gt;

&lt;br&gt;
&lt;input type=&quot;range&quot; id=&quot;grade-slider&quot; style=&quot;width:160px;&quot; min=0 max=1 value=0.5 step=0.01&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;okr-grade-sentence&quot;&gt;Beat our Q1 financial targets | Grade: &lt;strong id=&quot;grade&quot; class=&quot;grade&quot;&gt;0.50&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Key Results&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;key-results-list&quot;&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Achieve &amp;gt; $10M in product revenue&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;International sales of at least $2M&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Customer churn rate under 5%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;textarea id=&quot;assessment&quot;
          class=&quot;assessment&quot;
          placeholder=&quot;Reflect here on the progress you've made this quarter...&quot;&gt;
&lt;/textarea&gt;

&lt;button id=&quot;submit&quot; class=&quot;submit-btn&quot;&gt;Grade this OKR!&lt;/button&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot; src=&quot;./libs/snap.svg-min.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot; src=&quot;./libs/sweetalert.min.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot; src=&quot;./main.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>motion design (part 1 of 2)</title>
      <link>sketches.kevinsalter.me/articles/8-motion-design-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">sketches.kevinsalter.me/articles/8-motion-design-part-1/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-align: center; display:block;&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;/giphy awesome things&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Wondering what’s going to pop up?!  Of course you are!  GIFs are awesome.  Movement is awesome. Motion is awesome.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;text-align: center; display:block;&quot;&gt;You’re awesome.  &lt;code&gt;/giphy high five&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;why-complicate-ux-with-frivolous-ui-animations-&quot;&gt;Why Complicate UX with Frivolous UI Animations??!?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For starters, they’re fun!!  A well-placed, tasteful animation can delight users, add to the stickiness of an application, and even help to express a brand’s personality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course there are more pragmatic reasons for animation as well.  A skillfully done animation can make an application appear faster.  Check out how the &lt;a href=&quot;http://dribbbox.com/&quot;&gt;Dribbbox&lt;/a&gt; homepage uses a bouncy animation of its name to distract you from the fact that the site is working in the background to retrieve a heavy payload of images (which then get used as part of the background design) using the Dribbble API.  This is a welcome alternative to the typically mundane loading GIF.  By the time the images load and fade in, the typical user would feel like they’re getting a proper experience, and wouldn’t know there was a delay at all!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;margin:0 auto;text-align:center;width:100px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;sketches.kevinsalter.me/articles/8-motion-design-part-1/loading.gif&quot; alt=&quot;yawwwwwn&quot;&gt;&lt;em style=&quot;font-size:11px;font-weight:200;color:#777;margin:15px 0 30px 0;display:block;&quot;&gt;yaaaawwwwn…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another practical application of animation is to help maintain context for the user, and show the relationship between states as they change.  A great example is YouTube’s current play/pause button.  Go ahead and give the play button a few clicks and watch the icon morph into a new shape, clearly leaving the user with an understanding of before/after.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;margin:0 auto 25px;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/TWXZy2dOuBc?rel=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Motion can also give the user reassuring feedback.  For example, Material Design and iOS both give the user feedback when something is tapped or clicked.  This is usually in the form of a subtle ripple and quick flash.  Showing cause and effect is an important factor in interaction design.  In the case of Material Design, the ripple originates from where the user taps or clicks on the element, as you can see here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;margin:0 auto 25px;text-align:center;width:300px;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;video autoplay loop tabindex=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;width:300px;&quot;&gt;
        &lt;source src=&quot;//material-design.storage.googleapis.com/publish/material_v_4/material_ext_publish/0B3T7oTWa3HiFOFFrMHpqN3NMQkU/animation_responsiveinteraction_userinput_materialresponse.webm&quot; type=&quot;video/webm&quot;&gt;
        &lt;source src=&quot;//material-design.storage.googleapis.com/publish/material_v_4/material_ext_publish/0B3T7oTWa3HiFcDFYVWp0QUVGSEE/animation_responsiveinteraction_userinput_materialresponse.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot;&gt;
        &lt;/video&gt;
    &lt;em style=&quot;font-size:11px;font-weight:200;color:#777;margin:15px 0 30px 0;display:block;&quot;&gt;Material Design Response&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, motion can help inform the visual hierarchy of a screen in an equally important way as the size and colour of elements.  Motion catches the eye and can draw a user’s attention to that section of the screen.  Good examples of this are when items are animated-in as they’re appended to a list, or when a numbers swells-in above a notifications icon to indicate unread messages.  Even a looping animation might be effective to highlight the next element that the user should (or even must) interact with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;margin:0 auto 45px;text-align:center;width:100px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;sketches.kevinsalter.me/articles/8-motion-design-part-1/jingle.gif&quot; alt=&quot;jingle&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is there an amazing example of motion design in an app you’ve used, or someone’s portfolio you’ve checked out before?  &lt;a href=&quot;sketches.kevinsalter.me/articles/8-motion-design-part-1/#disqus_thread&quot;&gt;Post a link!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;be-careful-&quot;&gt;Be Careful!&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A quick word from &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/HgY-xvyIlzY&quot;&gt;Buzz Killington&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You need a license for these things!!  Not really, but they’re easy to overdo.  The most pleasing and effective animations typically show a great deal of restraint and good taste.  They have to be applied consistently, just like any other enhancement, to avoid negatively surprising the user, or worse still, confusing them and putting them off task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;read-the-docs&quot;&gt;Read The Docs&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Motion design existed well before the digital age, and even &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.discovery.com/history/archaeology/prehistoric-movies-120608.htm&quot;&gt;thousands of years ago, depending who you ask&lt;/a&gt;.  But modern animation and motion design as we know it arguably began in the 1930s with Disney’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/93206523&quot;&gt;12 basic principles of animation&lt;/a&gt;.  These principles are echoed and expanded upon for the digital age in Google’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/design/spec/animation/responsive-interaction.html#responsive-interaction-user-input&quot;&gt;Material Design Animation&lt;/a&gt; docs and also Apple’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/library/ios/documentation/UserExperience/Conceptual/MobileHIG/Animation.html#//apple_ref/doc/uid/TP40006556-CH57-SW1&quot;&gt;iOS Human Interface Guidelines&lt;/a&gt;.  The fact that the two largest mobile platforms have documentation on how animations should be done is quite telling.  Although, while it’s helpful to have these written guidelines, it’s important to remember that, in the end, motion is one of those things that just has to &lt;em&gt;feel right&lt;/em&gt; and fit in the context it’s used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A note on browser support:&lt;/strong&gt; With our recent, unceremonious kicking of IE8 to the curb, we gain a lot more options for leveraging awesome, state-of-the-art web technologies to create animation!  There are still a number of challenges, but it helps.  🎉&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;margin:0 auto 80px;text-align:center;width: 450px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;sketches.kevinsalter.me/articles/8-motion-design-part-1/browser-support.png&quot; alt=&quot;browser support&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;down-wit-opp&quot;&gt;Down Wit’ OPP&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there are some &lt;a href=&quot;http://species-in-pieces.com/&quot;&gt;pretty&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/ca/mac-pro/&quot;&gt;amazing&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/juliangarnier/pen/idhuG&quot;&gt;examples&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com/dashboard/iphone&quot;&gt;web-based&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.github.com/program/&quot;&gt;animations&lt;/a&gt;, I’d like to highlight a couple UI-specific animations that I really like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;margin:0 auto;text-align:center;width:500px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;sketches.kevinsalter.me/articles/8-motion-design-part-1/kickstarter.gif&quot; alt=&quot;kickstarter icon&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br&gt;

This is &lt;a href=&quot;https://dribbble.com/shots/2075475-KickMaterial-Kickstarter-Material-app-icon&quot;&gt;one example&lt;/a&gt; of an animated app icon– in this case, for a fan-made Android Kickstarter app.  It’s not &lt;em&gt;necessarily&lt;/em&gt; a piece of the UI, although it could be used in-app or on the homescreen of a mobile device.  Really, I think that creating an animated icon tailored for a specific app is just a cool opportunity to express the values and personality of a brand while showing off some design facility.

&lt;div style=&quot;margin:30px auto;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p data-height=&quot;500&quot; data-theme-id=&quot;0&quot; data-slug-hash=&quot;oXLroX&quot; data-default-tab=&quot;result&quot; data-user=&quot;suez&quot; class='codepen'&gt;See the Pen &lt;a href='http://codepen.io/suez/pen/oXLroX/'&gt;Pull Down to Refresh (Paper Plane)&lt;/a&gt; by Nikolay Talanov (&lt;a href='http://codepen.io/suez'&gt;@suez&lt;/a&gt;) on &lt;a href='http://codepen.io'&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;script async src=&quot;//assets.codepen.io/assets/embed/ei.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.materialup.com/blog/create-material-design-animation&quot;&gt;This airplane animation&lt;/a&gt; falls squarely into the inspiration category for me.  What this design lacks in practicality it more than makes up for in its execution and fun, surprise factor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin:0 auto;text-align:center;width:500px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;sketches.kevinsalter.me/articles/8-motion-design-part-1/stripe-form-shake.gif&quot; alt=&quot;stripe form shake&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way Stripe handles &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/bridge-collection/improve-the-payment-experience-with-animations-3d1b0a9b810e&quot;&gt;the error response on this form&lt;/a&gt; with an animation is really cool.  As they explain, they took an interaction that was frustrating users and facilitated the situation with motion.  It’s like the form is shaking its head &lt;em&gt;no&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;making-7geese-move&quot;&gt;Making 7Geese Move&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which parts of 7Geese could benefit from some kind of motion design? Another way of asking that question could be, which actions or tasks in 7Geese should &lt;em&gt;feel like more of an event&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The application already has a nice animation when you update your progress; even hovering the key result progress percentage animates nicely into the “check-in” button.  But what else could be done?  Here’s a short list of events in the app that could be enhanced by motion:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;checking into objectives (and updating assessments)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;closing objectives&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;completing cycle requirements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;recognition (animated badges!?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;when a list is filtered and items are added/removed (&lt;em&gt;i.e.&lt;/em&gt; People Management page)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;when new messages appear at the top of the feed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;when new notifications are available (icon background colour and the number indicator in the nav bar)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;when modal dialogs appear/disappear&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;sketches.kevinsalter.me/articles/8-motion-design-part-1/#disqus_thread&quot;&gt;some other idea you just thought of…&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
In &lt;strong&gt;Part 2&lt;/strong&gt; I’ll use &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.adobe.com/ca/products/aftereffects.html&quot;&gt;After Effects&lt;/a&gt; or maybe &lt;a href=&quot;http://snapsvg.io/&quot;&gt;Snap.svg&lt;/a&gt; to make one of these sketches move.  Also, I might need to do some consulting on the finer points of SVGs… Kevin Fales, I’m looking at you. 👀
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article-end&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;annotation&quot;&gt;
    7Geese animated icons concepts
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;sketches.kevinsalter.me/articles/8-motion-design-part-1/7geese-animated-icons.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;animated icons&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>reflection as a module</title>
      <link>sketches.kevinsalter.me/articles/7-reflection-module/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27  Aug 2015 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">sketches.kevinsalter.me/articles/7-reflection-module/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
“By three methods we may learn wisdom: first, by reflection, which is noblest; second, by imitation, which is easiest; and third, by experience, which is the most bitter.” &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;~ Confucius
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seven months ago, just after joining the flock at 7Geese, I did my first stand-up, group reflection.  I remember feeling weird about it, since I’d never really made an effort to consciously engage in a process of personal reflection before, let alone share that reflection with a room full of my colleagues. &lt;em&gt;(yes, I’m reflecting in my post about reflection…)&lt;/em&gt;  However, in the months following, I’ve grown to appreciate the power of the reflection process in all aspects of my life.  I’m interested to see what form this process could take as a module in 7Geese, as I feel it’s in strong alignment with the platform’s goal to further empower the Individual Contributor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;reflection-what-s-the-point-&quot;&gt;Reflection: What’s the point?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, the greatest strength of the reflection process lies in its proclivity to harvest the learnings of personal experience and apply that knowledge to future tasks.  Said another way, &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.mit.edu/cil/web_scripts/www/Critical%20Moments%20Methodology%20Brief%20CoLab.pdf&quot;&gt;it requires the reconstruction and reinterpretation of the experience illuminated by its results&lt;/a&gt;.  We can learn from our mistakes (redos) and not be doomed to repeat them.  We can gain a clarity that sparks decisive action. In the startup world, people &lt;a href=&quot;http://firstround.com/review/the-most-dangerous-leadership-traps-and-the-15-minute-daily-practice-that-will-save-you/&quot;&gt;can’t afford to have low learning efficiency. They must milk each experience for maximum learning. Reflection is the key for accelerating your learning curve&lt;/a&gt;.  And by being good learners, we become good teachers by sharing that expertise with the rest of the team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;tone-context-and-habit&quot;&gt;Tone, Context, and Habit&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When composing personal thoughts and feelings in solitude before sharing them with colleagues in a group situation, it’s important to establish the right tone.  People should feel safe to publish their reflection in a conversational, clear, truthful way.  They should be able to fearlessly talk about wins and identify road blocks knowing that their teammates are there to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QhXJe8ANws8&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&quot;&gt;support and collaborate&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;(&amp;lt;— highly, highly recommend this video)&lt;/em&gt;  Ideally they would publish their reflection habitually as part of a timely, consistent cycle.  This not only creates a record of their progress and a powerful feedback loop with teammates, but also holds the individual accountable to maintaining the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;methodologies&quot;&gt;Methodologies&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve come across several methodologies that would be really interesting to try and interpret and apply in the context of software and 7Geese.  It’s out of the scope of this post to explore different methods, but quickly, it’d be cool to explore &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.mit.edu/cil/web_scripts/www/Critical%20Moments%20Methodology%20Brief%20CoLab.pdf&quot;&gt;Critical Moment Reflection Methodology&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://firstround.com/review/the-most-dangerous-leadership-traps-and-the-15-minute-daily-practice-that-will-save-you/#text_0c261222fe6c4890b423ad167d4e4e5f&quot;&gt;Integral Theory&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reflective_practice#Gibbs_1988&quot;&gt;Gibbs model of reflection&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reflective_practice&quot;&gt;any of these, really&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this post, I’d like to narrow the focus to imaging what it would be like to combine our current workflow of Weekly Priorities with Reflection (wins, obstacles, proud, learning, redos) in a way that allows for engagement and feedback from colleagues, which would ultimately obviate the Feedback module.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;workflow-ux-ui&quot;&gt;Workflow, UX, UI&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, how might the &lt;strong&gt;7Geese Model of Reflection™&lt;/strong&gt; look?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the highest level, you would enter your weekly priorities as a checklist at the start of the week, and reflect on those priorities and anything else significant that happened at the end of the week.  That would be the cycle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For entering Weekly Priorities, it’d be cool to have a TODO-list or &lt;a href=&quot;https://workflowy.com/demo/embed/&quot;&gt;workflowy&lt;/a&gt;-style interface to capture priorities in a standard, familiar way.  Arash had the awesome idea of potentially pre-populating this list with the person’s “redo” from the previous week as a way to help keep people accountable to themselves.  It’d also be cool if you were shown some kind of week-over-week graph that showed a completion percentage, or in some way represented your trend of success with your weekly priorities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reflection part of the module would be more involved.  First, we’ll need a way to address the priorities.  Unlike a TODO-list, I notice that people (including myself) tend not to evaluate priorities as complete/incomplete.  You might want to mark a task as “half done”, “ran out of time, moved to next week”, “complete”, “changed”, “delegated”, or some other evaluation.  Once the priorities list has been given attention, it would then be time to write a personal reflection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wonder if it’d be cool to choose which format your reflection takes based on a template, i.e. blank screen, list of headings (Proud, Learning, Redos), list of questions (“When was a moment this week where you felt like you were performing at the top of your capabilities?”), or even listing out the Weekly Priorities with space under each one to write an assessment.  This is where the platform could start to accommodate the different methodologies.  Also, it’d be extra cool if 7Geese asked you specific questions &lt;a href=&quot;http://sketches.kevinsalter.me/articles/5-no-ui/&quot;&gt;based on your current OKRs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m also wondering if a full-screen, distraction-free mode would be useful for this exercise.  And when you enter full-screen mode, it totally relaxes you by using the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.noisli.com/&quot;&gt;Noisli API&lt;/a&gt; to play the soothing sounds of nature in the background while you type… &lt;em&gt;(lol, obviously I’m kidding, but I actually tried a Markdown editor once that had that “feature”…it was the worst…)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Commenting and “liking” could take a different form in this module as well.  I can see a medium-style inline commenting system being really conducive to giving someone direct feedback closer to the context of where the person originally expressed a thought. &lt;em&gt;(Now that I’m thinking about that, it’d be interesting if in the “wins” section of someone’s reflection you could highlight the point and a medium-style contextual menu pops up with the ability to recognize that person for that thing.)&lt;/em&gt;  As for “liking”, it might be interesting to offer more of a range of reactions.  The main benefit of that would be that you’d have more ways to interact with the post on that level.  And by that I mean, I imagine 3 levels of interaction: 1) no interaction, 2) passive interaction (“liking”), and 3) engaged interaction (commenting).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, while commenting and “liking” are obvious staples for interacting with the finished posts, but in the interest of feeling safe and confident in publishing your personal reflection, this is one 7Geese module that would benefit form the ability to “edit” your post!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How would you imagine reflection functioning in 7Geese?  &lt;a href=&quot;sketches.kevinsalter.me/articles/7-reflection-module/#disqus_thread&quot;&gt;Let me know in the comments&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article-end&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;annotation&quot;&gt;
    reflection module concept sketch
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/7-reflection-module/reflection-module.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;full-screen reflection&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>feed me</title>
      <link>sketches.kevinsalter.me/articles/6-feed-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17  Aug 2015 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">sketches.kevinsalter.me/articles/6-feed-me/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week, there was a thread on 7Geese where Amin revealed that there had been a time where the “Post” functionality for the Feed on the homepage was &lt;em&gt;almost&lt;/em&gt; removed completely because 7Geese’s focus is not to be a communication portal like Yammer or Slack.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
At first this caught me by surprise (not the product differentiation, the thought of removing the ability to “Post”), but I thought about it for a while and started to envision how that change might look.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-thought-process&quot;&gt;The thought process&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Essentially, I have two overarching thoughts that I’m combining into this particular design of the homepage feed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you scroll through your feed, you’ll notice that (other than occasionally posting some meeting notes) we mainly use the “Post” functionality to enter &lt;strong&gt;Weekly Priorities&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Reflection&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(…I’m going to explore the idea of Reflection as its own module in next week’s post…)&lt;/em&gt;.  So, I’m imagining that those are two modules in 7Geese, similar to how Objectives, Recognitions, Feedback, and 1-on-1s are their own modules.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If feed items followed some sort of visual hierarchy, you’d be able to scan the feed more quickly and extract the information you need more easily &lt;em&gt;i.e.&lt;/em&gt; less actionable updates would appear smaller, while more actionable or significant items would appear larger.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;visual-hierarchy&quot;&gt;Visual hierarchy&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To establish the foundation of a visual hierarchy, I’ll start by defining the size of feed items in this new design to be one of three possible sizes: small, medium, or large.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Small&lt;/strong&gt; feed items would be infrequent actions, or non-actionable pieces of information.  For example, network updates such as “&lt;u&gt;@John Smith&lt;/u&gt; has joined 7Geese”, or “&lt;u&gt;@Sally Jones&lt;/u&gt; created a new department: Sales”, would likely appear as small, one-line messages.  We could still include the user’s avatar, and hyper-link their name, but that message would be visually deemphasized in the feed.  This also includes items that a user is not able to comment on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Medium&lt;/strong&gt; feed items could be thought of as semi-frequent actions that represent some kind of progress.  This kind of action could be checking into, assessing, or closing an objective.  Users would still be able to comment on these items from the feed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think Recognition is our only &lt;strong&gt;Large&lt;/strong&gt; feed item at this time, but I wonder what other kinds of messages might warrant this level of emphasis in the feed – closing objectives comes to mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, I’m envisioning something similar to GitHub’s version of the feed as shown on a Pull Request page. In my opinion, that’s the best representation of this kind of information I’ve seen in a user interface on the web.  If you know of an example that you think is amazingly designed, &lt;a href=&quot;sketches.kevinsalter.me/articles/6-feed-me/#disqus_thread&quot;&gt;let me know in the comments below&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;a-quick-note-on-functionality&quot;&gt;A quick note on functionality&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some functionality considerations that I’m not really going to explore in this post include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What kind of filtering do we want to keep/add/eliminate?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;currently we can filter by People:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My Departments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My Direct Team&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All Company&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and by Item Type:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Posts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Objectives&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;when someone checks in&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;when an objective’s status is updated, changed, or cleared&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;when a post is made on an objective&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recognition&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;when recognition is given/received&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Network Updates&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;@name&lt;/code&gt; has joined 7Geese!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;@name&lt;/code&gt; created a new department: Sales&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What kind of actions can a user take, and when?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;here I’m referring to the ability to “Like”, “Delete”, “Comment”, or “Edit” feed content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Should we support Markdown?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;of course I vote yes, but it’s not a small integration since it would ideally require the ability to edit posts, a markdown preview-mode, user education, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Should we support uploading images in-line?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;see sub-point above…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;item-types&quot;&gt;Item Types&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would be helpful and visually interesting to use an icon or symbol (more prominently than we do now) to represent the different item types that can possibly appear in the homepage feed.  Currently we have the 3 types listed above (when eliminating Posts), but just for fun I’m going to imagine that we also have a Weekly Priorities module and Reflection module – so that’s &lt;strong&gt;5 Item Types&lt;/strong&gt; in total:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Objectives&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recognition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weekly Priorities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reflection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Network Updates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The crux of this design is that I’m proposing we eliminate the tabbed area (recognition/post) above the homepage feed, and the only messages that populate the homepage feed would come from 7Geese modules.  That being the case, users would still be able to comment on items in the feed as they currently do, and would still be able to “Post” on the objective page feed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have I missed anything important here?  Any holes in my pattern of thinking? &lt;a href=&quot;sketches.kevinsalter.me/articles/6-feed-me/#disqus_thread&quot;&gt;Leave a comment&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article-end&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;annotation&quot;&gt;
    Idea #1 - a feed re-design with an emphasis on people (like the current feed)
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/6-feed-me/feed1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;a new feed #1&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;annotation&quot;&gt;
    Idea #2 – emphasis on tasks
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/6-feed-me/feed2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;a new feed #2&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;annotation&quot;&gt;
    icon brainstorming
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/6-feed-me/icon-brainstorming.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;icon brainstorming&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;annotation&quot;&gt;
    a lower fidelity view of how the new feed might fit into a different homepage layout
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/6-feed-me/homepage-layout.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;a new feed on the homepage&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>the best ui is no ui</title>
      <link>sketches.kevinsalter.me/articles/5-no-ui/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13  Aug 2015 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">sketches.kevinsalter.me/articles/5-no-ui/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A user interface (UI) is the means by which humans interact with machines in a way that makes it easy, efficient, and enjoyable to operate those machines in a way that produces the desired results.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
But how often do UIs completely under-deliver on that promise?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;pop-uis&quot;&gt;Pop UIs&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, I &amp;lt;3 UIs.  At the same time, I think this quarter-century-old quote is as relevant as ever:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    “The real problem with the interface is that it is an interface. Interfaces get in the way. I don’t want to focus my energies on an interface. I want to focus on the job…I don’t want to think of myself as using a computer, I want to think of myself as doing my job.” – &lt;a href=&quot;http://cs.nyu.edu/courses/spring98/G22.2280/UI-Introduction/sld072.htm&quot;&gt;Donald Norman (circa 1990)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s funny to think that 12 years later, &lt;strong&gt;Minority Report (2002)&lt;/strong&gt; would come out and designers would immediately start spending &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theawl.com/2013/02/how-minority-report-trapped-us-in-a-world-of-bad-interfaces&quot;&gt;a lot of time trying to repackage Steven Spielberg’s vision of the future&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s interesting to contrast that with the “slight future” world of &lt;strong&gt;Her (2013)&lt;/strong&gt; released about a decade later, where UI is actually hard to find.  People talk to their computers (no fiddling with keyboards or touch screens). Theo’s smart house turns its lights on/off as he moves between rooms, with no interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another interesting design decision in &lt;strong&gt;Her&lt;/strong&gt;, which makes for a great counterpoint to &lt;strong&gt;Minority Report&lt;/strong&gt;, is that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wired.com/brandlab/2014/01/will-influential-ui-design-minority-report/&quot;&gt;instead of overlaying our vision with a feed, as we’ve typically seen it, Theo gets a one piped into his ear&lt;/a&gt;.  I’ve been finding more, and more that the convention of “the feed” is being thought of as an anti-pattern, and according to some arguments, &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/matter/the-web-we-have-to-save-2eb1fe15a426&quot;&gt;antithetical to the true spirit of the internet&lt;/a&gt;.  Although, this is slightly ironic, considering a main concept of “the feed” is to deliver curated information to the end user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-best-interface-is-no-interface&quot;&gt;The best interface is no interface&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lately, I’ve been thinking more about the 3 principles laid out by Golden Krishna, who is one of the larger proponents and champions of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cooper.com/journal/2012/08/the-best-interface-is-no-interface&quot;&gt;the best interface is no interface&lt;/a&gt; (in fact, he may have coined the phrase, I dunno).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; I say specifically that I like the &lt;em&gt;principles&lt;/em&gt; because the name of the theory is an obvious false dichotomy, and that’s how flame wars that go nowhere get started. 🔥&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At a high level, I interpret the principles to be asking, “What is the &lt;em&gt;minimum&lt;/em&gt; interface that a user needs?”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
    “Good design is invisible. Minimum input, maximum output, with minimal conscious thought.” — &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theverge.com/2012/7/24/3177332/ia-oliver-reichenstein-writer-interview-good-design-is-invisible&quot;&gt;Oliver Reichenstein&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;principle-1-embrace-natural-processes&quot;&gt;Principle 1: Embrace natural processes&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to this principle, you as a designer analyze the situation first and identify the processes that already exist around the problem you’re trying to solve.  This is in contrast to saying, hey, I have all this great technology, now where can I apply it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://techcrunch.com/gallery/what-its-like-to-use-amazons-new-dash-buttons/?ncid=rss&quot;&gt;Amazon Dash&lt;/a&gt; buttons are a really interesting example of offering a screenless solution to interact with their service.  It’s funny that the idea was so outrageous that people thought it had to be an April Fool’s joke.  But for realz, my washer/dryer doesn’t need a screen and its own wifi connection where I need to log into my Amazon account and order more detergent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The example Krishna uses of how &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theverge.com/2015/3/17/8103593/golden-krishna-best-interface-is-no-interface-excerpt&quot;&gt;the BMW app&lt;/a&gt; gets it wrong is a great example of the flaws with having a technology-first approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He then outlines how he would apply the observational methods from his &lt;strong&gt;Cat Poet&lt;/strong&gt; acronym to begin designing a screenless solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;float:right;width:188px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/5-no-ui/catpoet.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;cat poet&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C. What is the typical &lt;strong&gt;context&lt;/strong&gt; for the activity?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A. Who are the primary &lt;strong&gt;actors&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;T. What’s the primary &lt;strong&gt;task&lt;/strong&gt; or goal?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P. What’s the typical &lt;strong&gt;process&lt;/strong&gt; you’d like to simplify?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O. What &lt;strong&gt;objects&lt;/strong&gt; typically exist in the environment?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;E. Does anything need to be &lt;strong&gt;explained&lt;/strong&gt; or communicated to the person(s) involved?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;T. What &lt;strong&gt;triggers&lt;/strong&gt; might indicate that the person wants to commit to that action?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, how would this look when applied to a problem we’re trying to solve at 7Geese?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Problem:&lt;/strong&gt; Help users &lt;strong&gt;assess and check into their OKRs in 7Geese&lt;/strong&gt; by aggregating information from 3rd party project planning applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Context&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At the office or at home, on laptop/desktop computer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Actors&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;employees, managers (could be further specified with personas)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Task&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;checking into objectives (which also includes updating KRs and assessment updates)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Process&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;log into 7Geese and navigate to the objective that needs updated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;gather information on how much progress has been made on an objective&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;enter a description/summary of what has happened&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;enter the specific numbers/details related to each KR&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assess OKR as “On/Off Track” and enter a status for the update (Max mentioned that there’s an opportunity for combining this with step #2)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Save the check in so that it appears in 7Geese and notifies colleagues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Objects&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;computer, desk, wifi, bluetooth, other software and devices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Explained&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the user needs to see the new state of their KRs (expressed as a ratio, percentage, dollar amount, or binary complete/incomplete)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the user also needs to be shown their new overall progress percentage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Triggers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the user has completed meaningful work in a 3rd party application such as Asana, Jira, or GitHub&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the owners/stakeholders of the objective are having a meeting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the objective has been completed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the quarter is ending&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The context could likely be fleshed out even more, but I think that this kind of approach is one nice way to solve a problem by starting with people and working back to technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;principle-2-leverage-computers-instead-of-catering-to-them&quot;&gt;Principle 2: Leverage computers instead of catering to them&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is just a slightly fancier way of asking, “Who’s in charge here?!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Screens are needy.  You’re stuck using them; it’s a chore.  You have to swipe, click, tap your way to what you need. Sometimes it’s necessary to interact with a screen, but other times you have to wonder…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I usually have my cell phone on ringer at home, and on vibrate when I’m out in the world– why doesn’t my phone notice and ask me about it if I’ve forgotten to turn on vibrate after leaving the house?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the title of one of my Calendar events contains the word “Meeting” and my status is “Show as Busy”, why doesn’t OS X turn on “Do Not Disturb” for me (or at least ask me)?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of calendars, this seems similar to what we’re doing with 1-on-1 scheduling; just trying to make logical connections for users to reduce their cognitive overhead.  But we’re really just scratching the surface.  OKR due dates could appear as calendar events, or cycle beginnings and endings (quarterly? triannually? etc.) could appear in calendars as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;font-size:14px;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Footnote:&lt;/em&gt; I’d say &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Machine_learning&quot;&gt;machine learning&lt;/a&gt; falls under this principle as well, but that’s a much bigger, much more complicated, much more expensive topic unto itself (which I know, like, nothing about).  &lt;a href=&quot;http://nerds.airbnb.com/aerosolve/&quot;&gt;AirBnB’s engineering team&lt;/a&gt; posts some really cool stuff on the topic if you’re interested, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;principle-3-adapt-to-people&quot;&gt;Principle 3: Adapt to people&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find this principle especially interesting.  Krishna uses the example of thinking back to when you first signed up for Gmail– it was awesome, everything was new, powerful, innovative…but where can it go from there?  The only way to keep giving gains to the end user is to either build more features, or execute an expensive, time-consuming re-design every few quarters to keep things fresh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reversing this curve reveals a more human-centric outcome.  For example, Nest.  There’s a shiny, conspicuous UI on Nest, for sure, but that’s just the front door of the product.  Over time it can learn your behaviour and, in the case of Nest thermometers, can adjust themselves automatically based on your patterns. This creates more value the more you use the product by saving you time and money while keeping things at a comfortable temperature.  So, the UI becomes less necessary as time goes on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At 7Geese we’re starting to re-imagine how our notifications and information architecture operate.  How should our application talk to users?!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using this principle as a guideline, I could imagine a time where 7Geese notices how a user likes to set their OKRs (i.e. maybe 3 OKRs every quarter), and prompts the user to engage with an &lt;a href=&quot;/articles/3-okr-builder-concept&quot;&gt;OKR builder&lt;/a&gt; a week before the current quarter ends, and save their OKRs as drafts that would then begin the following week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building off of that idea, I could also imagine 7Geese noticing the frequency that a user checks into each individual OKR, and again prompt the user to visit that OKR’s page and take action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I realize these last scenarios I’ve described rely on screens, but they speak directly to what I feel is a sister-principle at play here– reduce the cognitive load of the user so that I think of myself as “doing my job” and not “using a computer”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The future is simpler than you think.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;article-end&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;annotation&quot;&gt;
    below are the most elegant sketches of no ui you will never see
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/5-no-ui/no-ui.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;No UI&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>starting to imagine mobile recognition</title>
      <link>sketches.kevinsalter.me/articles/4-mobile-recognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06  Aug 2015 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">sketches.kevinsalter.me/articles/4-mobile-recognition/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While there are debates around how a modern employee recognition program might operate, it’s clear that there is tremendous value in being able to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.officevibe.com/facegame&quot;&gt;recognize your colleagues&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
…
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Seriously though, it’s obvious that showing appreciation and receiving kudos from teammates builds morale and makes people feel more connected to each other.  But should it be a core focus of a company, or is it just an annoying thing aimed at ‘millennials’?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-7geese-flavour-of-love-recognition&quot;&gt;The 7Geese flavour of &lt;del&gt;love&lt;/del&gt; recognition&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At 7Geese, recognition badges represent a company’s core values; awarding badges to colleagues then helps strengthen each person’s alignment to those values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love that simplicity.  It’s also a really nice parallel to the way OKRs strengthen the alignment of everyone’s goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-is-recognition-good-for-&quot;&gt;What is recognition good for?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For many 7Geese users, being recognized by a co-worker is a &lt;a href=&quot;http://genius.com/Alex-schultz-lecture-6-growth-annotated&quot;&gt;“magic moment”&lt;/a&gt;– an instant where a user feels the platform delivering its core value and building its stickiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since recognition can come from anyone (peers, managers, reports) it can help to unify teams, proactively reinforce good performance, and foster a sense of appreciation and belonging across the entire team.  New employees being on-boarded can quickly get a direct sense of what that company is about.  And the public nature of recognition means people are noticing that your work is getting noticed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zooming out a bit, the trend of recognition given over a period of time could be an interesting data point for company leaders to help gauge employees’ alignment to the company’s core values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;arguments-against-recognition-and-way-better-counterarguments-&quot;&gt;Arguments against recognition (…and way better counterarguments)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s also important to define what recognition is &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt;– &lt;em&gt;i.e.&lt;/em&gt; it doesn’t acknowledge any employee’s tenure, metrics or stats related to their job (there are no leaderboards!), and it’s not meant to gamify an employee’s training experience (meaning, you don’t get a ‘prize’ after each level), for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That being said, there are still a few arguments we’ve received against recognition’s effectiveness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most reasonable one I’ve heard so far is that it can be annoying at larger companies to see a feed full of recognitions, some of which you may not care about.  There’s likely a case to be made for allowing users to opt in/out of which recognitions hit their feed and, conversely, if employees wanted to be more private, and limit the publicity of recognitions they have received (even though that kind of defeats the purpose…).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another complaint is that people are being recognized too frequently, and that it can feel like a bit of a popularity contest.  The answer to this could be as simple as teaching people to ask &lt;em&gt;“Is this something that could happen everyday?”&lt;/em&gt;, and if the answer is &lt;em&gt;yes&lt;/em&gt;, it’s not recognition.  Recognition must be authentic and genuine, or else it’s not worth the pixels on the screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also think it’d be an interesting experiment to limit the frequency of recognitions– &lt;code&gt;more scarcity == more valuable&lt;/code&gt;.  For example, maybe you can only give out 1 recognition per week, or only recognize one person per month.  The purpose wouldn’t be to limit users, but just ensure some common sense guidelines were being followed.  The details would have to be worked out, but it might help people to give proper consideration before recognizing someone, and make recognitions harder to ‘abuse’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, there’s the argument that “I’m not a millennial, I don’t need to be recognized for doing my job.”  In my opinion, that’s straight bull$h!t.  But don’t take my word for it!  Harvard Medical School published an article a few years ago explaining how &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.health.harvard.edu/newsletter_article/in-praise-of-gratitude&quot;&gt;gratitude helps people feel more positive emotions, relish good experiences, improve their health, deal with adversity, and build strong relationships&lt;/a&gt;.  And Harvard is never wrong, so…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;is-mobile-the-right-format-&quot;&gt;Is mobile the right format?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since our Q3 meeting, I’ve been interested in the idea of each module of 7Geese being its own mobile app.  It makes sense, since we have some customers who only use 7Geese for recognition, and I’ve read feedback from another customer who wants to use 7Geese only for doing his 1-on-1s.  We’ve also got an “OKR only” tier, so it makes sense that we’d have an OKR only mobile app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So let’s think for a minute about why mobile would be a good format for an individual module like recognition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the simplest terms, the act of giving recognition is quick and easy to do.  It’s an impulsive action that doesn’t require any preparation.  I could be on the SkyTrain on my way home from the office and remember that I wanted to recognize a colleague.  I whip out my phone, and 💥.  That kind of ease and convenience would also facilitate timely recognition which, as we know, &lt;a href=&quot;http://support.7geese.com/hc/en-us/articles/204411167-Tips-On-Recognizing-a-Teammate&quot;&gt;(is more effective)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;some-mobile-best-practices&quot;&gt;Some mobile best practices&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are a few considerations when designing a mobile experience:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;elements should be sized appropriately&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;design for fat fingers, pictorial icons&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://tympanus.net/Development/CardExpansion/&quot;&gt;use animations&lt;/a&gt;, maybe &lt;a href=&quot;http://tympanus.net/Development/AnimatedSVGIcons/&quot;&gt;SVG morphing icons&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;this is supposed to be fun!!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there might be better &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lukew.com/ff/entry.asp?1950&quot;&gt;alternatives to dropdowns&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how does the navigation work?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how many clicks/swipes are required to accomplish a certain task?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://uxmyths.com/post/654026581/myth-all-pages-should-be-accessible-in-3-clicks&quot;&gt;not that that matters?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mobile internet is slow&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;is the app simple, and the payload to the browser as small as it can be?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;design patterns: &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.intercom.io/why-cards-are-the-future-of-the-web/&quot;&gt;cards&lt;/a&gt; vs &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.uxpin.com/6774/5-creative-mobile-ui-patterns-navigation/&quot;&gt;grids&lt;/a&gt; vs &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nngroup.com/articles/image-vs-list-mobile-navigation/&quot;&gt;lists&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how much of the app can i navigate using only one hand?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;notes-on-some-of-the-screens-we-ll-need&quot;&gt;Notes on some of the screens we’ll need&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;login&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;navigation&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I’m leaning towards a fullscreen nav motif throughout the app (i.e. popovers, dialogs, and navigation would all take up the full screen while they’re being used)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;browse colleagues&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;also browse departments or teams?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;choosing a colleague then opens recognition form with the person pre-selected&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;recognition form (for giving recognition)&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;recognize individuals, groups, and departments?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;choose user(s)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;write description&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;choose badge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;checkbox toggles: notify recipient’s manager? department(s)?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;list (feed) of recognition given out&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;ability to filter by person / team / badge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;each list item links to individual recognition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ability to “like” or share without having to go to individual recognition (swipe left on iOS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;individual recognition pages&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I imagine it would be really similar to the card-style layout we use for this already&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;with comments&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;ability to “like”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;social sharing (maybe admins can turn this off in settings)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;social sharing button’s overlay/dialog (full screen)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;list of available badges with descriptions&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;choosing a badge shows the description of that badge (full screen)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;when in full screen, there’s an ‘x’ to close the overlay, and a CTA button to give that badge to someone, which then opens the recognition form with that badge pre-selected&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Admins:&lt;/em&gt; create and edit badges&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;badge name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;description of badge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;which departments can use it?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;upload an image&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;by the way, Digital Ocean has &lt;a href=&quot;http://drbl.in/mZXI&quot;&gt;some really nicely designed core values badges&lt;/a&gt;, worth checking out&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article-end&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;footnote-1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;note:&lt;/em&gt; each rectangle in the wireframes below is the size of an iPhone 6 screen
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;annotation&quot;&gt;
    mobile interface for giving recognition
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/4-mobile-recognition/give-recognition.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Giving Recognition&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;annotation&quot;&gt;
    giving a recognition, looking at a recognition, navigation, and social sharing
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/4-mobile-recognition/recognition-and-nav.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Recognition and Nav ideas&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;annotation&quot;&gt;
    3 possible UIs for choosing a coworker to recognize
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/4-mobile-recognition/choose-a-colleague.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Choose a colleague ideas&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/4-mobile-recognition/choose-a-colleague2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Choose a colleague ideas 2&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OKR builder concept</title>
      <link>sketches.kevinsalter.me/articles/3-okr-builder-concept/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">sketches.kevinsalter.me/articles/3-okr-builder-concept/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week’s sketch and concept started out as something I just thought would be funny– the idea that as you enter your objectives and key results into fields in the UI, the software “lints” your input and gives you feedback akin to a spell-checker.  But in the end, I realized that it actually has a couple of interesting connections to how a tech product delivers core value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More on that in a minute, but first:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;okr-builder-and-linter-concept&quot;&gt;OKR Builder (and linter) Concept&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is really conceptual, since a good OKR has so many subjective qualities (i.e. it’s difficult to algorithmically determine if an objective is “attainable, but still ambitious like a stretch goal” or if it aligns with a company’s “organizational culture”).  Then again, if I’m using the spell-checker analogy, a spell-checker can’t ensure your writing is grammatically correct and elegant, so it kind of works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the sketches below, the interface is essentially a blank screen (à la Medium) with a field for the user to enter their first objective.  The user would press &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;tab&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; to jump from the objective to each key result, with new fields appearing as the user progresses (so, ideally no clicking would be required to create 3 objectives with 3 key results).  As the user types, the words are scanned on every keystroke, and feedback is given to the user based on what they’ve entered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, I’ve noticed that 99% of objectives that I’ve seen defined in the OKR pattern begin with a verb (i.e. Increase, Reduce, Improve, Implement, etc.), so that would be helpful feedback to show the user.  For key results, the possibilities might be even more numerous considering they’re more quantitative in nature.  In fact, most key results contain numbers, which is another data-point that an OKR builder could look for in the user’s input.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; the example OKR in the sketches below is completely contrived (obvs), and only intended for demonstration purposes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, if I were to imagine a set of OKR linting rules as a config file similar to those we use in code linters, it might look something like this, &lt;code&gt;okr-linter.json&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
    &amp;quot;no_leading_verb_in_objectives&amp;quot;: {
        &amp;quot;level&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;error&amp;quot;
    },
    &amp;quot;numbers_in_objectives&amp;quot;: {
        &amp;quot;level&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;warn&amp;quot;
    },
    &amp;quot;too_many_ands_in_objective&amp;quot;: {
        &amp;quot;level&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;warn&amp;quot;
    },
    &amp;quot;no_numbers_in_keyresults&amp;quot;: {
        &amp;quot;level&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;error&amp;quot;
    }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h4 id=&quot;connecting-some-dots&quot;&gt;Connecting Some Dots&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the largest challenges at any tech company is onboarding.  And, when it comes to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.preact.com/saas-churn-causes-and-prevention&quot;&gt;leading causes of churn in SaaS products&lt;/a&gt;, it’s often a huge factor.  At 7Geese it’s especially interesting since we’re also selling our customers on the adoption and implementation of the OKR methodology, as well as the software platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another challenge that any tech company faces is forming some kind of “growth hacking” strategy.  For example, Facebook used the metric of getting users to “10 friends in 14 days” as a benchmark for deciding if users were adequately engaged with the product and would receive enough of the core value of the product to a level where they would be retained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, to combine those ideas, imagine this OKR builder tool were set up in such a way that it required the user to create “3 objectives with 3 key results every 3 months”, and then guided the user through the process with automatic, instant feedback. 💥&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s obviously an over-simplification, but it’s food for thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article-end&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;annotation&quot;&gt;
    okr builder concept
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/3-okr-builder-concept/1-okr-builder-overview.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;OKR Builder Concept Sketch&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;annotation&quot;&gt;
    ‘objective starts with a verb’ error tooltip
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/3-okr-builder-concept/2-objective-verb-error-tooltip.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Objective Starts with Verb Error Tooltip&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;annotation&quot;&gt;
    ‘objective contains a number’ warning tooltip
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/3-okr-builder-concept/3-objective-warning-tooltip.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Objective Number Warning Tooltip&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;annotation&quot;&gt;
    ‘objective’s scope is possibly too broad’ warning tooltip
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/3-okr-builder-concept/4-objective-and-warning-tooltip.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Objective Uses And Warning Tooltip&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;annotation&quot;&gt;
    ‘key result doesn’t contain a number’ error tooltip
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/3-okr-builder-concept/5-kr-error-tooltip.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Key Result Number Error Tooltip&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1-on-1 scheduling alerts</title>
      <link>sketches.kevinsalter.me/articles/2-1-on-1-alert/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">sketches.kevinsalter.me/articles/2-1-on-1-alert/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This quick sketch was inspired by the upcoming 1-on-1 scheduling project for 7Geese, and also the proposed “Explore new Information Architecture (IA) approaches for 7Geese” project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea of the platform shifting from being objective oriented (lol… no? …) to being focused on talent management and employees (as proposed in the IA project definition) is actually quite profound.  To me, at the highest level, it’s the difference between whether I keep the 7Geese application open in a browser tab all day, every day, or only open it once a week to check into my objectives.  Huge difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To expand on that, if the application is going to be open all the time, it will be because it’s giving me new and direct feedback.  As a user, I’ll then want to treat the app as a dashboard for project related progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How is my team doing, especially on the projects I’m directly involved in?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where am I needed?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What should I do next?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Answering these questions for users could improve a couple of the answers that Dave recently received from users to the question &lt;a href=&quot;https://7geese.atlassian.net/wiki/pages/viewpage.action?pageId=12714000&quot;&gt;Can you tell us why you checked-in today?&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;1-on-1-alert&quot;&gt;1-on-1 Alert&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a culture of Continuous Performance Management, the habit of regular 1-on-1s is vital.  Furthermore, if you have a management role, this can involve participating in different 1-on-1s as both a facilitator and subject.  The case can then be made for the value of having a prominent alert that keeps the user engaged in the 1-on-1 workflows within 7Geese.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The top-right area of the navigation seems like a logical place for an alert like this to live since it would be close to other in-app notifications.  Inside the popover the user is presented with a concise, plain English representation of their pending 1-on-1 commitments (basically, any 1-on-1s that are in Draft Mode for that user).  There are two possible actions that can be performed on each list item:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;click the calendar icon to go directly to Google calendar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;clicking the body of the message would redirect the user to the individual page for that particular 1-on-1.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;article-end&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;annotation&quot;&gt;
    scheduled 1-on-1 alert concept
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/2-1-on-1-alert/1-on-1-alert.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;1-on-1 Alert Concept Sketch&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>the gameplan</title>
      <link>sketches.kevinsalter.me/articles/1-gameplan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2015 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">sketches.kevinsalter.me/articles/1-gameplan/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, I’ve created an &lt;a href=&quot;https://7geese.com/okrs/&quot;&gt;OKR&lt;/a&gt; for my Q3 at &lt;a href=&quot;http://7geese.com&quot;&gt;7Geese&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;“Improve my ability to think critically about feature design/implementation and strengthen user empathy through sketching” &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-1&quot; style=&quot;text-decoration:none;&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, and tagged it with the &lt;code class=&quot;learn-and-grow&quot;&gt;Learning and Growth&lt;/code&gt; label.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I’ve been meaning to get back to sketching UI and UX workflow ideas for a while now.  It’s a great way to brainstorm and explore ideas &lt;em&gt;away from the computer&lt;/em&gt; for several reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;more&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it’s the fastest/cheapest way to ideate and explore a few trains of thought quickly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;thinking with your hands and physical tools like pencil and paper provide a nice change in pace from digital tools&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sketching is low fidelity, which tends to invite commentary and foster better conversations around the ideas being presented&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, with so many interesting things on the 7Geese feature roadmap, this will be a useful way jot down some ideas before we form teams and start building things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;footnote-1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;
    &lt;strong class=&quot;pull-left&quot; style=&quot;margin-right:10px;&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;div&gt;My objective was previously called “12 sketches in 12 weeks”, but I improved it after watching &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/133095368&quot;&gt;Creating a GREAT OKR and Quarterly Planning Process&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;article-end&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;annotation&quot;&gt;
    sketches from past projects
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/1-gameplan/dashboard-sketch.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dashboard Sketch&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/articles/1-gameplan/phone-sketch.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Phone Sketch&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>